

Ali Asghar Momeni Vesalian

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - JAVA

PROFILE

Gender: Male

Nationality: Persian **Birth Date**: 6/30/1985

Software engineer with a strong background in design and development on Java platform for more than 10 years. Keen learner and problem solver with a passion for algorithms, architecture, high throughput systems and Big Data. Highly experienced in developing financial and banking systems.

EDUCATION

Master of Science from Tehran Markazi Azad University in Software Engineering from September 2015 to Present.

Bachelor of Science from Qazvin Azad University in Software Engineering from September 2003 to September 2008.

LANGUAGES

English

Persian

CONTACT

Email: momeni.vesalian@gmail.com

Mobile: +36 70 421 6654

LinkedIn: Momeni Vesalian's profile Address: Flat 5, No. 16, Kikelet St.,

Budapest, Hungary

WORK EXPERIENCE

EPAM Systems

Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2019 - Present

- As a key developer, I design and implement a search project.
- As a key developer, I design and implement a web crawler project.

Sava Arman Kish (Bitex)

Senior Java Developer

Jun 2018 - Mar 2019

- I worked as the chief architect of the exchange project.
- I designed the architecture model and implemented architectural APIs.
- I designed and implemented the matching engine.

Navaco (Maskan Bank)

Senior Java Developer

Mar 2017 - Jun 2018

- I worked as a member of CORE Banking architecture team.
- I designed the architecture model and implemented some architectural APIs.
- I designed and implemented lending overnight calculation.

Caspian (Parsian Bank)

Senior Java Developer and Designer

Sep 2014 - Mar 2017

- I worked as a member of the Lending team.
- I designed and implemented conversion's architecture model.
- I wrote 30000+ lines of Java and PL-SQL code.

Rayan Eghtesad Novin (Eghtesad Novin Bank)

Software Designer

May 2013 - Sep 2014

- I worked as a member of the Lending team.
- I designed repayment and settlement functionalities.

Caspian (Parsian Bank)

Java Developer and Designer

Sep 2009 - May 2013

- I worked as a member of the Lending team.
- I designed and implemented repayment, settlement, installment calculation.
- I wrote 150000+ lines of Java code.



Ali Asghar Momeni Vesalian

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - JAVA

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Java 8	Spring
Design Patterns	Spring Boot
SOA	Spring MVC
Microservices	Spring Batch / Quartz
Event Driven Architecture	Spring Security
Software Architecture Patterns	Spring Data / JPA
Big Data Architecture	Spring WebFlux
Big Data Concepts	Vert.x
Live Migration	Hibernate / EclipseLink / iBatis
Concurrent Programming	Redis
Reactive Programming	Oracle PL/SQL Development
RESTful Web Services	Gradle / Maven
Docker and Docker Compose	Git / Subversion
CI / CD	Test Driven Development
Jenkins	JUnit / Mockito / JMockit
Swagger	Hadoop / Spark / Storm
Eureka / Ribbon / Hystrix Netflix	UML / Agile and RUP Methodologies
OSGi / Blueprint	CORE Banking Systems
Apache Karaf	Lending System Developer
Azure Search	Crypto Currency Exchanges
<u>IAIEX</u>	Exchange Developer